Vengeance...
Dammit!
It was Scar!
He knew that Marcoh was involved in the extermination?!
Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
I'll let you know when I get more information.
Isn't being an assistant to the Führer President the same thing as being taken hostage?
You sure you'll be okay?
To look at it in a positive light, it means I have the chance to assassinate him in his sleep.
That's scary.
Oh, right.
Do me a favor and let the Colonel know that Scar is still lurking around.
Got it.
Lieutenant.
Yes?
Thanks for telling me about Ishbal.
The 520 Cens Promise
Al!
Brother! What's up?
Wow... So that's how things were in Ishbal...
She was willing to tell me everything, despite me being a kid.
Alchemists are people who pursue the truth...
...and yet...
...we didn't even know about things so close to us.
So the Colonel is looking at the future that'll take place after he accomplishes his goal.
The future that'll take place after he accomplishes his goal, huh...
Al, what do you plan to do after you get your body back?
Let's see...
For starters, I want to taste Winry's apple pie.
What about you, Brother?
I haven't really thought about it, since I've always been so intent on getting my limbs back.
I guess I'll start off by going around to Granny and Master and letting them know first.
Yeah, they've really done a lot for us.
They'll all greet us with smiles, right?
Yeah.
We'll be able to see their smiles, right?
We're in a tight spot, but that sort of cheered me up.
I've got something good to tell you, too.
We couldn't use alchemy at that time.
And it turns out others couldn't, either.
Then what about that girl and Scar...
That's right. They were the only ones who could.
There's something different about their alchemy...
Something we're not aware of...
Yeah.
We're not at a dead end yet.
Left?!
That midget left?!
Yeah. Early this morning.
Did she say where she was headed?!
Nope.
We've got to look for her!
All of Central? Without a single lead?
We do have a lead.
What's this?
A gift.
In that case...
...couldn't you have brought me magazines with a lot of cute girls in 'em?
Don't be slacking off while we're gone, all right?
You're heading off already?
Yeah.
I'm off to taste some western specialty dishes.
You'd better take care of this place while we're gone!
I will.
Later.
Make sure you eat a lot and grow bigger and stronger.
Protect everyone while I'm away.
Sergeant Fuery.
Hey.
Warrant Officer Falman!
You still haven't left yet?
I came to return something to the Colonel.
It sure was a short stay in Central...
Were you transferred to Southern Headquarters, Sergeant?
Yes, sir. Opposite from you.
I bet it's cold over in Northern Headquarters...
Well then, so long, Sergeant Fuery.
Farewell. May we meet again.
Sorry to bother you, Colonel.
Lieutenant.
I came to pick up something I left here.
I see.
Apparently, Scar is still lurking about.
Then I have to be extra careful.
Since I no longer have a skilled bodyguard.
Please don't die.
Of course.
Sorry to put you through so much trouble.
Perhaps I chose the wrong person to follow.
"If I ever stray away from my path, shoot me right away."
That was the deal.
Your actions are still within the permissible range.
You're too kind, Lieutenant.
So long, Colonel.
So long.
Please don't slack off, okay?
Sure...
My pawn...
I guess my hobbies got the best of me...
My bishop...
Yes, sir! It is an honor!
My rook...
Thanks.
My knight...
I'm stupid, so I had a rough time at the military academy.
And...
If you wish, I'll follow you to the depths of Hell.
...even my queen was taken from me.
But, it's too early...
...for checkmate.
Like this! This is what the cat looks like.
I'm looking for a little girl carrying this thing around.
Sorry, please ignore that alien he's holding up.
No one knows anything about that black and white cat...
I wonder if she left Central already?
Fullmetal.
Colonel!
I see. Eastern Alchemy from Xing, huh?
Got it.
I'll ask around about it, too.
To be honest, I didn't really want to ask you for any favors...
Oh, yeah. Speaking of being in debt...
...give me my money back.
Watch where you're going!
So you remembered...
How much do I owe you again? 500 cenz?
520 Cenz!
Don't try to play it off!
What the hell! You're so stingy!
At this rate, you'll never make it big!
Sorry...
Actually, I'm going to hold on to this.
I'll return it when you become the Führer President.
Who told you?
Lieutenant Hawkeye.
She told me about Ishbal, too.
Fullmetal.
You can keep the change for now,
but I'll be getting it back for sure.
When that time comes, I'll borrow money from you again.
With the promise "I'll give this back to you when you turn this country into a democracy".
And when you get that back, I'll borrow from you again and make you agree to something else.
Which means I have a long life ahead of me, huh?
That's right.
Quit worrying the Lieutenant!
Thanks for the ride!
Later.
You sure took a while.
I thought I'd be waiting here until I went bald.
Yo.
Oh, my! Roy!
It's been so long!
You look well, Vanessa.
Long time no see, Roy.
Good evening, Madam Christmas.
How have you been?
Not very well at all.
I came here to liven up.
What can I start you out with?
I'm actually recovering right now, so alcohol is a no-no.
I'll be asking for the specialty, Madam.
You got it.
Lieutenant General Grumman, you have a call from Central from a lady by the name of Madam Christmas.
Oh?
Seriously... Please don't tell civilians about our secret line.
It just means that I'm not completely useless.
Someone has a task for this old geezer.
You lost your arm, failed to protect the young master,
and are now reduced to such a state...
Hey! What the hell are you doing?!
You still call yourself a chosen member of the Yao Clan?!
PLACEHOLDER
Have some honor!
Cut it out, old man!
She's injured!
I said stop!
Did you really lose it...
Did you really lose your arm...
I'm sorry, Grandfather.
I'm sorry...
Fool...
As we promised, we'll set you up with an automail mechanic right away.
No.
Thank you for your consideration.
We shouldn't ask you to help us any further.
We'll somehow find an automail mechanic on our own.
But we can't just leave you like this!
Now that the enemy knows what Lan Fan looks like, we can't take any actions that may involve your friend in this.
Okay.
Thanks for the consideration.
You saved my granddaughter's life.
I thank you.
I ain't a doctor that should be receiving gratitude-
Dr. Nox, thank you so much.
G-Get the hell out of here!
I'm not kind enough to let you weirdos stay forever!
Seriously!
It seems the Emperor's condition is worsening by the day.
We must get the young master back and return to our country with the stone as soon as possible.
Let's go.
Yes, sir.
Just wait, you fiends.
We shall be back soon.
I'll never forget my gratitude to you for saving me.
Dr. Nox, thank you so much.
And now  I'm starting to act like a doctor after all this?
One sec.
Who is it?
Oh.
Hey, Dad.
It's been so long.
Are you doing okay?
Of course.
We had some business around here, so...
You've gotten taller.
Don't you think you've lost some weight?
You're one to talk.
Is your work keeping you busy?
Yeah, I've been performing on corpses as always-
Well, wait.
I treated two live patients this week.
Isn't that funny?
Me, saving people's lives?
Dad, I'm studying to become a doctor.
I know that you've been going through a rough time ever since you returned from Ishbal.
Yet, you didn't quit your job.
I love you, Dad! As the doctor you are and have always been.
Idiot...
Why don't you come in?
The coffee's not too tasty, but have a cup or two.
Wow, it's such a mess in here!
Come, let's get this place cleaned up while Dad makes us coffee.
God, if you really do exist, please overlook this.
Even someone like me can enjoy a cup of coffee with his family, right?
And with this, Ishbal has completely fallen under the control of the army.
Well done, Major Kimblee.
How do you like the philosopher's stone?
It's wonderful.
I was able to perform transmutations beyond my dreams while ignoring the concept of equivalent exchange.
Good.
Make a record of the details and submit it.
Now give us the stone back.
What have you done, Kimblee?!
Now, it's only you all who know where the stone is.
You bastard!
What the hell?!
What happened?!
What was that?!
Whoops.
Come out, Kimblee. You're being released.
What's this about?
You don't need to know.
Is it an order from the higher-ups?
Shut up.
Besides, why weren't you put on
death row after killing five officers?
What trick did you use?
Nothing in particular.
Maybe it's because of my natural virtues?
Don't make me laugh, you bomberman!
What the hell are the higher-ups thinking, releasing a freak like you?
Mr. Jailer, thanks for taking care of me for all this time.
Don't come back again.
Just a token of my gratitude.
Don't tell me...
Wait!
Stop! Please, take it off!
Kimblee!!!
It's a boring old toy.
Please give it to your kid or something.
Well then, farewell.
Now...
It's been a while, Kimblee.
Congratulations on your release.
So it was you all who let me out.
Yup.
We've run into a labor shortage.
Which means, you have a job for me?
Do you happen to remember Doctor Marcoh?
The scientist who helped create the philosopher's stone, right?
I remember him very clearly.
He may...
...have escaped.
"May have"?
It's still not clear yet.
One of the chimeras we placed as a watchdog was gone.
Marcoh is an alchemist especially skilled in organic transmutation.
The corpse may have been a substitute.
And to make matters worse,
there's a possibility he's on the run with Scar, an Ishbalan.
So, how does that sound to you...
...as someone who was ordered to annihilate Ishbal, the Crimson Alchemist?
Let's see...
If it's an Ishbalan that I forgot to kill, then it's hard to let this one pass.
You're allowed to kill Scar on sight.
But bring Marcoh back alive.
You released me from jail for something like that?
Once we capture Marcoh, we're going to wipe a town off the map just to show him who he's messing with.
Isn't that a pleasant job?
You're really a nasty person, aren't you?
I can finally use this, after all this time.
That may not be enough if we're
planning to destroy an entire town.
Wow...
Did you make this out of Ishbalans, too?
It's made out of the guys who were researching the stone under Doctor Marcoh.
You truly are nasty.
Why did you help me escape?
I...
There are still things I need to ask you.
About the alchemist named Kimblee, and...
...there were parts I couldn't understand in the research documents my brother left me.
Research documents?
"There's something strange about this country's alchemy" are the words he left me before he died.
Something about that should be written in the documents.
You're a skilled alchemist.
You'll be able to comprehend it, won't you?
Something strange about this country's alchemy?
Master. The little girl came back.
Mister Scar! You were okay!
Huh? We have another friend with us?
He's not a friend.
His name is Marcoh.
He's a man who created a philosopher's stone and assisted in the Ishbalan Extermination.
A philosopher's stone! For immortality?!
Mister Marcoh, do you know how to make the stone?!
How?! Please, tell me!
Well, that's...
Stop.
You shouldn't wish for such a thing.
I only destroyed the exterior of his face.
Please stop his bleeding.
Okay!
It's better to destroy his face so others won't be able to tell who he really is.
Are you okay, Mister Marcoh?
Let's go.
Huh? To where?
To the place I hid the documents.
North.
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
The figure hidden all this time reveals himself with a smile.
With that, a new threat endangers the tangled web Central is.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 32, The Führer's Son.
The Führer's Son
Would it be better to not know?
Or perhaps...